<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="66"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[ORGANIZERS
                                                智慧城市物聯網國家重點實驗室(澳門大學)
                                                Laboratório de Referência do Estado de Internet das Coisas para a Cidade Inteligente
                                                   (Universidade de Macau)
                                                State Key Laboratory of Internet of Things for Smart City (University of Macau)
         SPONSORS]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[2022


           Conference Program

           Day Two - 5 NOV 2022                                                                                                               
     
                        
  
	    
  
         
           
  
  
 
                                                                                                                                               
    
                                                                                                                                            
      
                 
  
        
       
  
       
     
 
 
     	  
                                                                                                                                                                              
  
         
                                                                                                                                             
  
    

                                                                                         ­                                       
 
                                                                                                                                                 
   
                        
     
        
 
  
         
     
    
      Conference Program    •   07
                                                                                                                                    ­
                        
        
                                                      ­ 
       	                                       
     

                 
   		   
         
          
     
 
 
         
 
                                                                                            
       ­ 
    
 
                         
                                         
              
       	
 
  
 
            
                    ­   
                                                                 
                    ­ 
    

                                                               

                                     
  
    
                                                                                                                                                 


                                                                                                                                               
     

                  
  
 ­           
        
   
 
       
  
       
                                                                                                                                                                                                                  
    
 
 
 
                                                                                                                                                                             
 
                                                                                                                                            
           
                            
                                                                                                             
  
       
                                                        
                      
 
                         
                               
  ­
       
             ­ 
    
 
                    ­ 
  	
 
    	               
                                      
      
  
 
                                  
     
                     
 
         
  
            
   
                     ­ 
    
 	                                                                                                          
     

                  
  
         
      
         
     
     
                                                                                                                                                                                                                              
                                                                                                                                            
      
               
 
 
                                 
 
 
 
                          
                                                                                                                  
  
    
                     

                                                         
   
           
            ­ 
       
                         
                           ­ 
 
 
             
                      
     
                                  
 
                  ­ 
     
                                                                                                   ­        
   
                   

          
 ­    
    
 
        
  
   
                    ­ 
    
                                                                                                             
     

                 

          
                          

  

         
                                                                                                                                    ­   
            
                        
                                                                                                                
  
    

                                                                    
                   ­ 
       
                         
                           ­      
      
                          
           ­  
                         

                    ­ 
    
 
 	
   
                    ­ 
    
                                                                                                            
     

                      
  
           
      
          
      
                                                                                                                                                                                                                     
 
        
 
 
 
                                                                                                                                                                            
         
                                                                                                                                            
           
                            
                                                                                                             
  
       
                         
                                  

  
   
               
    ­ 
     
                    ­ 
  	
 
    	                 
                   
    
           
                                        
     

                     ­ 
    
 	                                                                                                          
     

                    
 
       
  
     
       
 
     
       
                                                                                                                                            
      
                  
       
   
  
                    
 
 
          
                          
                                                                                                                  
  
    
                     
      
                       
 
       
                                                   	

                
            ­ 
     
      ¡
                         
                            
      
      
    
         ­                     ­                            
 
                   ­ 
     
                        
   
                                                                ­        
   
                                     
                  
       
                    ­ 
    
                                                                                                             
     

                     
         
            
   
           
   
 
 
   
                                                                                                                                    ­   
                           
     
                                      
                        
                                                                                                                
  
    

                                                        
   
             
    
        ­ 
    
    
 	
                         
                                  
                                 
                                                

                    ­ 
    
 
 	
                                                                                                        
     
   
                                                           
          
                    ­ 
    
                                                                                                            
     

                    
      
         
  
              
     
     

                                                                                                                                                                          
                                                                                                                                            
                                                               
    
 
 
 
                                                                                                                                            
  
       

                                                                                                                                    ¡­
                                                                                                                                                
     
                                                           
    
                                                                                                                                             
    
                                                             
   
   
                                                                                                                                    ­
                                                                                                                                    ­
                                                                                                                                                                                     
  
                                                                                                                                    ­]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="14"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="15"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="16"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="17"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="18"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="19"><![CDATA[2022











           Invited









           Speakers]]></page><page Index="20"><![CDATA[2022


                                                                 Invited Speakers    Victoria, Canada
                                                                 Lin CAI


                                                                Professor  •  IEEE Fellow  •  EIC Fellow
                                                                 University of Victoria



                                Self-Evolving and Transformative (SET) Protocol
                                Architecture for 6G

                                The fusion of digital and real worlds in all dimensions will be the driving force
                                for future sixth-generation (6G) wireless systems. Ubiquitous in-time and on-
                                time communication services between humans, machines, robots, and their
                                virtual counterparts are essential, and they expand from the ground to air, space,
       Sensing and Communications Track    •   17
                                underground, and deep sea. 6G systems are not only data pipelines but also large-
                                scale distributed computing systems with integrated sensing, processing, storage,
                                communication and computing capabilities. It is challenging to build ubiquitous
                                and intelligent 6G systems, handling stringent quality-of-service (QoS) requirements,
                                providing a rich set of communication modes, including unicast, multicast, broadcast,
                                in-cast, and group-cast, and supporting user-centric mobile applications. In this talk,
                                we introduce a new protocol architecture, Self-Evolving and Transformative (SET)
                                architecture that can provide a wide range of control functions, and be intelligently
                                configured for different types of 6G applications and networking environments. Its
                                design principles, potentials, and open issues are discussed. We also introduce a use
                                case applying the architecture to develop a mobility-aware multi-path QUIC protocol
                                for satellite networks.





                                                                 Invited Speakers    Shenzhen, China
                                                                 Fan LIU


                                                                 Assistant Professor
                                                                 Southern University of Science and Technology



                                On the Fundamental Tradeoff of Integrated Sensing and
                                Communications Under Gaussian Channels

                                Integrated Sensing and Communication (ISAC) is recognized as a promising
                                technology for both the next-generation wireless networks and radar systems. In
                                this talk, we shall provide a general framework to reveal the fundamental tradeoff
                                between sensing and communications (S&C), where a unified ISAC signal is exploited
                                to perform dual-functional tasks. In particular, we define the Cramér-Rao bound
                                (CRB)-rate region to characterize the S&C tradeoff, and propose a pentagon inner
                                bound of the region. We show that the two corner points of the CRB-rate region
                                can be achieved by the conventional Gaussian signaling and a novel strategy
                                corresponding to the uniform distribution over the Stiefel manifold, respectively.
                                Moreover, we also offer our insights into transmission approaches achieving the
                                boundary of the CRB-rate region, namely the Shannon-Fisher information flow.]]></page><page Index="21"><![CDATA[2022


           Invited Speakers    Beijing, China
           Zhaoming LU

            Associate Professor
            Beijing University of Post and Telecommunications                                                       Sensing and Communications Track    •  18


           Joint Vehicular Localization and Reflective Mapping Based
           on Team Channel-SLAM

           This talk addresses high-resolution vehicle positioning and tracking. In recent work,
           it was shown that a fleet of independent but neighboring vehicles can cooperate
           for the task of localization by capitalizing on the existence of common surrounding
           reflectors, using the concept of Team Channel-SLAM. This approach exploits an
           initial (e.g. GPS-based) vehicle position information and allows subsequent tracking
           of vehicles by exploiting the shared nature of virtual transmitters associated to the
           reflecting surfaces. In this talk, we show that the localization can be greatly enhanced
           by joint sensing and mapping of reflecting surfaces. To this end, we propose a
           combined approach coined Team Channel-SLAM Evolution (TCSE) which exploits
           the intertwined relation between (i) the position of virtual transmitters, (ii) the shape
           of reflecting surfaces, and (iii) the paths described by the radio propagation rays, in
           order to achieve high-resolution vehicle localization. Overall, TCSE yields a complete
           picture of the trajectories followed by dominant paths together with a mapping
           of reflecting surfaces. While joint localization and mapping is a well researched
           topic within robotics using inputs such as radar and vision, this paper is first to
           demonstrate such an approach within mobile networking framework based on radio
           data.






           Invited Speakers     Paris, France
           Marco Di Renzo


           Professor • IEEE Fellow • IET Fellow • AAIA Fellow
           Paris-Saclay University Paris


           Reconfigurable Intelligent and Holographic
           Surfaces for Wireless Communications -
           On Modeling the Mutual Coupling

           A Reconfigurable Intelligent Surface (RIS) is a planar structure that is engineered
           to have properties that enable the dynamic control of the electromagnetic waves.
           In wireless communications and networks, RISs are an emerging technology for
           realizing programmable and reconfigurable wireless propagation environments
           through nearly passive and tunable signal transformations. RIS-assisted
           programmable wireless environments are a multidisciplinary research endeavor. This
           presentation is aimed to report the latest research advances on modeling, analyzing,
           and optimizing RISs for wireless communications with focus on electromagnetically
           consistent models that account for the mutual coupling.]]></page><page Index="22"><![CDATA[2022


                                                                Invited Speakers     Beijing, China
                                                                Lingyang SONG


                                                                Professor
                                                                Peking University



                                Reconfigurable Holographic Surfaces: A New
                                Paradigm to Holographic Communications for 6G

                                The future sixth generation wireless communications look forward to constructing
                                a ubiquitous intelligent information network with high data rates. To fulfill such
                                challenging visions, the reconfigurable holographic surface (RHS) is developed as
                                a promising solution due to its capability of accurate multi-beam steering with
       Sensing and Communications Track    •   19
                                low power consumption and hardware cost. Unlike the conventional phase-
                                controlled antennas, RHS can control the radiation amplitude of the reference
                                wave propagating on the metasurface by leveraging the holographic technique.
                                Such amplitude-controlled holographic beamforming triggers new challenges
                                since a new beamforming scheme needs to be developed to handle the complex-
                                domain optimization problem subject to the unconventional real-domain amplitude
                                constraints. Both analytical and simulation results verify the significant data rate
                                improvement of the proposed scheme.








                                                                 Invited Speakers    Greenbelt, US
                                                                 Beibei WANG

                                                                 Vice President
                                                                 Origin Wireless, Inc.


                                Wi-Fi Can Do More:
                                Towards Ubiquitous Wireless Sensing

                                Turning a Wi-Fi device into a ubiquitous sensor, which not only adds a brand new
                                dimension to the functions, capabilities, and applications of all Wi-Fi systems, but
                                also revolutionizes how sensing, especially human-centric sensing, is practiced. Wi-
                                Fi Sensing utilizes ambient Wi-Fi signals to analyze and interpret human and object
                                movements, underpinning many sensing applications such as motion sensing,
                                sleep monitoring, fall detection, etc. These new sensing functionalities can benefit
                                the global Wi-Fi ecosystem including integrated circuit manufacturers, device
                                manufacturers, system integrators, application developers, and ultimately end users.
                                In this talk, we introduce the concepts, principles of Wi-Fi Sensing, and share our
                                unique technologies that have been deployed for real-world applications. We foresee
                                that Wi-Fi Sensing will enter billions of devices and millions of homes, creating a
                                smarter space for a smarter life.]]></page><page Index="23"><![CDATA[2022


           Invited Speakers     Tokyo, Japan
           Celimuge WU


           Professor
           University of Electro-Communications                                                                     Sensing and Communications Track    •  20



           Empowering Federated Learning in
           IoV with Fuzzy Logic-based Client Selection

           Federated learning is a promising paradigm for achieving distributed intelligence by
           protecting user privacy in Internet-of-Vehicles (IoV). Considering limited computing
           and communication resources, it is important to select appropriate clients from a
           huge number of users to participate in the training process. The problem of choosing
           proper clients is particularly complex due to the heterogeneity of network users,
           including the differences in the data, computation capability, available throughput,
           and samples freshness. This talk introduces a fuzzy logic based client selection
           scheme to address this issue. The scheme considers the number of local samples,
           samples freshness, computation capability, and available network throughput
           based on a fuzzy logic approach. Extensive evaluation results show that the scheme
           outperforms existing baselines.






           Invited Speakers     Santiago, Chile
            Jinsong WU


           Professor
            University of Chile



           Environmental Sustainability and Intelligence
           as well as General Green Technologies
           Although the term of green has been often used to refer to energy consumption
           reduction or energy efficiency by many people and literatures, green actually
           should refer to environmental sustainability in more general senses. Environmental
           sustainability issues have been important topics for recent years, which has impacted
           and will further impact individuals, enterprises, governments, and societies.
           Environmental sustainability is not simply regarding reducing the amount of waste
           or using less energy, but relevant to developing processes leading to completely
           sustainable human society in the future. The long term consequences of the relevant
           serious issues have not yet been fully forecasted, but it has been generally accepted
           in many communities that immediate responses are necessary. From 30 November
           to 12 December 2015, the 21th United Nations Climate Change Conferences of
           the Parties (COP 21) was held in Paris, France, as the a historical breakthrough and
           milestone towards securing the future Earth, a global agreement on the reduction
           of climate change, the text of which represented a consensus of the representatives
           of more than 193 countries attending it, which was a profound milestone for global
           environmental sustainability. Nowadays there is another significant tendency on data
           driven intelligence. This talk would discuss the history, technical issues, challenges,
           and new trends of data driven environmental sustainability and Intelligence. Further
           this talk will extend the view to general green technologies.]]></page><page Index="24"><![CDATA[2022
                                           2022

                                                                 Invited Speakers     Macau, China
                                                                Yuan WU


                                                                 Associate Professor
                                                                University of Macau



                                Green Federated Learning:
                                A Wireless Power Transfer Approach

                                The past decades have witnessed a growing development of distributed Machine
                                Learning (ML) with its applications in various wireless services. As one of the key
                                paradigms of distributed ML, Federated learning (FL) allows a group of end-devices
                                to report their locally trained models to a central parameter-server for aggregating
       Sensing and Communications Track    •   21
                                the global model, instead of directly sending the raw data to the central parameter-
                                server, which thus brings the advantages of preserving the data privacy of the end-
                                devices as well as saving the bandwidth consumption for delivering the raw data to
                                the parameter-server. However, periodically executing the local model training as
                                well as reporting the trained model-data to the parameter-server result in significant
                                energy consumption to end-devices which usually suffer from limited energy
                                capacities. To address this challenging issue, this talk will focus on the discussions on
                                the design of green Federated Learning. In particular, we will leverage the recently
                                advanced wireless power transfer to enable a sustainable and efficient federated
                                learning and illustrate the joint optimization of wireless power transfer strategy,
                                learning strategy, and resource allocations.]]></page><page Index="25"><![CDATA[2022


            Invited Speakers     Xiamen, China
           Longbiao CHEN                                                                                            AI and Big Data Track    •  22


           Associate Professor
           Xiamen University



 Green Federated Learning:   Spatio-Temporal Urban Data:
 A Wireless Power Transfer Approach  Sensing, Analytics, Ad Applications

           Spatio-temporal data collected from urban environments (e.g. taxi trajectories)
           carry high-dimensional location and time attributes, containing rich information
           about urban development, human mobility, and environment change, etc. Recently,
           thanks to the rapid development of Internet of Things and mobile network
           technologies, large volumes of spatio-temporal have been collected, transmitted,
           and stored. However, current research on spatio-temporal urban data face several
           challenges, including inconsistent data quality, over-simplified analytical models,
           and limited application scenarios. In this talk, we present our recent work on the
           sensing, analytics, and applications of various spatio-temporal urban data in Xiamen
           University, and discuss the potential framework for spatio-temporal data-based urban
           computing.






            Invited Speakers     Beijing, China
            Wei CHEN

            Principal Researcher
            Microsoft Research Asia (MSRA)

           Optimization from Structured Samples：
           An Effective Approach for Data-driven Optimization


            Traditionally machine learning and optimization are two different branches in
            computer science. They need to accomplish two different types of tasks, and they
            are studied by two different sets of domain experts. Machine learning is the task
            of extracting a model from the data, while optimization is to find the optimal
            solutions from the learned model. In the current era of big data and AI, however,
            such separation may hurt the end-to-end performance from data to optimization
            in unexpected ways --- a recent result shows a fundamental limitation that directly
            optimizing from data samples is not achievable even when the separate model
            learning and model-driven optimization can be effectively executed. In this talk,
            I will introduce an approach called optimization from structured samples (OPSS)
            to tightly integrate learning and optimization by carefully utilizing the structural
            information from the sample data to adjust the learning and optimization algorithms.
            In particular, I will show how to overcome the above limitation when maximizing the
            (stochastic) coverage functions from structured data samples even when a model
            cannot be accurately learned from the data. OPSS is an effective approach for the
            paradigm of data-driven optimization, and it has applications in online advertising,
            influence maximization and other data-driven optimization tasks.]]></page><page Index="26"><![CDATA[2022


                                                        Invited Speakers     Fribourg
                                                        Philippe Cudré-Mauroux


                                                        Professor
                                                        University of Fribourg


                                Software Systems for Heterogeneous Hardware
       AI and Big Data Track    •  23
                                and Advanced Data Processing Platforms
                                Many large computer clusters offer alternative computing elements in addition to
                                general-purpose CPUs. GPU and FPGAs are very common choices. Two emerging
                                technologies can further widen the options in that context: in-network computing
                                (INC) and near-storage processing (NSP). These technologies support computing
                                over data that is in transit between nodes or inside the storage stack, respectively.
                                There are several advantages to moving computations to INC and NSP platforms.
                                Notably, the original computation path does not need to be altered to route data
                                through these subsystems; the network and the storage are naturally present in
                                most computations. In this talk, I will describe the evolutionary steps that led to INC
                                and NSP platforms and discuss how they can improve critical computing paths in
                                large-scale data-intensive systems. I will also present a number of recent hardware-
                                software co-designed systems that were recently deployed in my lab in collaboration
                                with Stanford, UCSD, and Hanyang University.]]></page><page Index="27"><![CDATA[2022


           Invited Speakers     Ningbo, China
 Philippe Cudré-Mauroux   Li DONG                                                                                   AI and Big Data Track    •  24


           Assistant Professor
           Ningbo University


           Physical Anti-copying Semi-Robust
           Watermarking for QR Codes

           QR code has been widely applied in anti-counterfeiting scenarios, where a unique
           QR code is attached (prints or pastes) on the surface of the authentic product. End-
           user can use mobile devices to scan and decode the QR code, and then verify the
           authenticity of products through an online anti-counterfeiting system. However,
           there is serve flaw in such a QR code-based anti-counterfeiting solution. The genuine
           QR code can be physically replicated by scanning and printing. Considering that the
           authentic QR code is printed and published, the malicious counterfeiter can easily
           scan, restore, and replicate a counterfeit QR code, which can pass the authentication
           as well. This physically illegal copying attack violates the unique QR code for one
           item principle and poses great threats to the QR code based anti-counterfeiting.
           In this talk, we present a physical anti-copying semi-robust watermarking system
           for QR codes.  Specifically, the authentic and counterfeit channels that a QR code
           experiences were investigated. By exploiting the distortion characteristics between
           the authentic and counterfeit channels, a semi-robust watermark embedding system
           was devised, where the watermark bit is embedded by modulating the relationship
           between two carefully selected transformed coefficients. Finally, to obtain a valid and
           recognizable binary QR code image, a random binarization procedure was applied.
           The final resultant watermark appears as white-dot pattern resides the black module
           of the QR code, which is robust to the authentic print-scan but fragile to physically
           illegal copying. Experimental results demonstrated the effectiveness of the proposed
           watermarking system. This work made the first step towards exploring semi-robust
           watermarking for combating physically illegal copying.]]></page><page Index="28"><![CDATA[2022


                                                                 Invited Speakers     Hong Kong, China
                                                                 Chao HUANG

                                                                 Assistant Professor
                                                                 University of Hong Kong



                                Self-supervised Recommender Systems
       AI and Big Data Track    •  25
                                Recommender systems are playing an increasingly critical role to alleviate information
                                overload and satisfy users' information seeking requirements in a wide spectrum
                                of online platforms. However, the ubiquity of data sparsity and noise notably limits
                                the representation capacity of existing recommender systems to learn high-quality
                                user (item) embeddings. Inspired by recent advances of self-supervised learning
                                (SSL) techniques, SSL-based representation learning models benefit a variety of
                                recommendation domains. Such methods have achieved new levels of performance
                                while reducing the dependence on observed supervision labels in diverse
                                recommendation tasks. This talk will provide a systemic review of state-of-the-art SSL-
                                based recommender systems. To be specific, this talk will summarize and categorize
                                existing work of SSL-based recommender systems in terms of recommendation
                                scenarios. For each type of recommendation task, the corresponding challenges and
                                methods will be presented in a comprehensive way. Finally, some future directions
                                and open questions will be raised to inspire more investigation on this important
                                research line.






                                                                 Invited Speakers     Hefei, China
                                                                 Defu LIAN

                                                                 Professor
                                                                 University of Science and Technology of China


                                Sequential Location Recommendation and Beyond


                                Location recommendation plays an important role in many applications such as
                                mobility prediction, route planning and location-based advertisements. In this
                                talk, I first cover recent advance on sequential location recommendation, from the
                                perspective of loss function, negative sampling and geography encoder. Following
                                that, I further introduce a highly-efficient-and-effective recommenation algorithm -
                                RecForest, which can outperform the SOTA effecient recommendation algorithms.
                                Finally, based on the existing research outputs in our team, we further introduce a
                                highly-modularized and inference-efficient recommendation library -- RecStudio.]]></page><page Index="29"><![CDATA[2022


           Invited Speakers     Hong Kong, China
           Yupeng LI                                                                                                AI and Big Data Track    •  26


           Assistant Professor
           Hong Kong Baptist University



           Towards Understanding COVID-19 Vaccination
           Stances Based on Interaction Graph:
           A Novel Dataset and its Applications

           COVID-19 has long been a global pandemic. Regardless of the documented
           effectiveness of COVID-19 vaccines against the disease, as per statistics given by
           the World Health Organization (WHO), the worldwide vaccination rate at present
           is still far from ideal. To boost the vaccine uptake, understanding people’s stances
           towards COVID-19 vaccination might be the primary considerations. Various popular
           online social platforms have gathered a colossal amount of user data related to the
           pandemic, including user-generated contents and user interactions representing
           the written expressions of users and the user-to-user interactivity, respectively. These
           data can potentially be exploited to learn user stances. Compared with the traditional
           methods like surveys and polls, understanding people's stances based on the data
           of online social platforms has the advantages of real-time, multiple information
           sources, and lower cost. In practice, while we can obtain user stances explicitly
           expressed in user-generated contents, there are some users who prefer not to reveal
           their stances in these contents. For these users, their stances are usually embedded
           in their interactions with other users. In this talk, we present a large-scale and novel
           dataset that consists of an interaction graph of COVID-19 vaccination stances based
           on the Twitter user data we collect. In addition, we investigate an application of
           the proposed dataset, the task of which is detecting user stances based on the
           interaction graph. To the best of our knowledge, this is the first to study the problem
           of automatic COVID-19 stance detection based on the interaction graph. We believe
           that our research can help corresponding entities make better use of the online social
           platform data to estimate and understand the real-time trend of the public stances
           towards vaccination, and then formulate relevant policies to overcome vaccine
           hesitancy. The arduous race to increase vaccine uptake could benefit from such
           understanding.]]></page><page Index="30"><![CDATA[2022


                                                                 Invited Speakers     Shanghai, China
                                                                 Zhihao TANG

                                                                 Associate Professor
                                                                 Shanghai University of Finance and Economics



                                Order Selection Prophet Inequality
       AI and Big Data Track    •  27
                                In the classical prophet inequality, a gambler faces a sequence of items, whose
                                values are drawn independently from known distributions. Upon the arrival of each
                                an item, its value is realized and the gambler either accepts it and the game ends,
                                or irrevocably rejects it and continues to the next item. The goal is to maximize the
                                value of the selected item and compete against the expected maximum value of all
                                items. A tight competitive ratio of 21 is established in the classical setting and various
                                relaxations have been proposed to surpass the barrier, including the i.i.d. model, the
                                order selection model, and the random order model.
                                In this paper, we advance the study of the order selection prophet inequality, in
                                which the gambler is given the extra power for selecting the arrival order of the
                                items. Our main result is a 0.725-competitive algorithm, that substantially improves
                                the state-of-the-art 0.669 ratio by Correa, Saona and Ziliotto (Math. Program. 2021),
                                achieved in the harder random order model. Recently, Agrawal, Sethuraman and
                                Zhang (EC 2020) Xiao, Liu and Huang (AAMAS 2020) proved that the task of selecting
                                the optimal order is NP-hard. Despite this fact, we introduce a novel algorithm design
                                framework that translates the discrete order selection problem into a continuous
                                arrival time design problem. From this perspective, we can focus on the arrival time
                                design without worrying about the threshold optimization afterwards. As a side
                                result, we achieve the optimal 0.745 competitive ratio by applying our algorithm to
                                the i.i.d. model.]]></page><page Index="31"><![CDATA[2022


           Invited Speakers      Macau, China
           Xiaowei WU                                                                                               AI and Big Data Track    •  28


           Assistant Professor
           University of Macau


           Recent Developments in Fair Allocations
           of Indivisible Chores

           In this talk I will introduce some of the recent developments for the computation
           and approximation of fair allocation problem for indivisible chores, which is within
           the centre of computational social choice and algorithmic game theory. I will
           introduce the popular fairness notions for this problem, including Envy-freeness (EF),
           Proportionality (Prop), Maximin Share (MMS), and their relaxations.
           Compared to the allocation of goods, the chores allocation problem has not received
           sufficient attention until recently. In this talk, I will survey the recent results on the
           existence, computation, approximation, and efficiency of these fairness notions,
           under different settings. I will also introduce some of our recent results on the
           computation of PropX allocations, approximately EFX allocations and approximately
           MMS allocation. Some open problems for future research will also be introduced in
           this talk.]]></page><page Index="32"><![CDATA[2022


                                                                 Invited Speakers     Wuhan, China
                                                                 Xinyu CHEN


                                                                 Professor
                                                                 Huazhong University of Science and Technology



                                Transition Pathway Towards Carbon Neutral
       Smart Energy Track    •  29
                                Electrical Power Systems in China: Quantitative
                                Analyses Based on High-precision Models

                                The carbon-neutral transformation of the China's electrical energy systems involves
                                not only trillions of money in fixed asset investment, but also the energy supply
                                security and the healthy and stable development of the economy. Based on the
                                high-precision digital twin platform of the national electrical energy system, this
                                report will present the quantitative analysis on several key problems under the
                                backgroud of the carbon-neutral transformation of the electrical energy system: the
                                renewable energy resources and economics, the development layout of the offshore
                                wind power, the optimal investment planning of the electrical energy system, the
                                layout optimization of the energy storage and the hydrogen production, and the
                                coordinated development of electric vehicles and power grids. In addition, this
                                report will introduce the optimized transformation path of China's electrical energy
                                systems, and discuss about the policy and market mechanisms to guarantee the
                                secure and stable operation of the system.






                                                                 Invited Speakers    Hangzhou, China
                                                                 Yi DING


                                                                 Professor
                                                                 Zhejiang University


                                Reliability and Resilience Evaluation of
                                Integrated Energy Systems

                                The Power System is evolved into the form of Integrated Energy System (IES), whose
                                outstanding characteristic is the complicated interactions among multi-energy. With
                                the rapid development of energy conversion components, the coupling among
                                natural gas, heat, electricity and other energy becomes closer. However, the multi-
                                energy coupling may lead to the cascading failure of IES, which even cause the power
                                outage. Therefore, it is necessary to evaluate and optimize the reliability and resilience
                                of IES. To solve the problem mentioned above, we established a system reliability
                                evaluation model and method considering the dynamic characteristics of multi-
                                energy flow. Moreover, an optimization control strategy based on massive flexible
                                load to improve the reliability of IES were proposed.]]></page><page Index="33"><![CDATA[2022


            Invited Speakers    Nanjing China
           Wei GU                                                                                                   Smart Energy Track   •  30


           Professor
           Southeast University



           Exploration and Practice of Efficient Operation
           of Urban Intergrated Energy System

           Cities are the main battlefields for energy consumption and the "dual carbon"
           strategy. Breaking through the traditional energy system structure and developing
           the urban energy system integrated with electricity/gas/heat systems is an effective
           way to solve the energy and environmental crisis, and it is also a major demand for
           China's energy development strategy and the "dual carbon" strategy. This report
           will introduce the modeling, simulation and operation optimization methods of the
           electricity/gas/heat integrated energy system, and also the demonstration of the
           urban energy system that our research team is in charge of.







           Invited Speakers     Hong Kong, China
            Yunhe HOU


            Associate Professor
            The University of Hong Kong


           Resilient Operation of Urban Power
           Grid under New Energy Paradigm

           A reliable power supply is essential for the maintenance of the vital societal and
           economic well-being of people. Empowering the emerging energy infrastructure
           with resilience has been well identified as one of the crucial tasks to modernize the
           energy infrastructure. This talk will present the urban energy systems operation under
           extreme weather events with renewable energy integration. The proactive resilient
           operating strategies against unfolding extreme events and coordination strategies
           under different stages of extreme events will be demonstrated. The potential
           applications of novel power-electrics devices for enhancing resilience will also be
           involved in this talk.]]></page><page Index="34"><![CDATA[2022


                                                                 Invited Speakers    Beijing, China
                                                                 Zechun HU


                                                                Associate Professor
                                                                Tsinghua University


                                Flexibility Aggregation and Dispatch of Large-
       Smart Energy Track    •  31
                                Scale Distributed Energy Resources
                                The aggregation of distributed energy resources (DERs) draws much attention
                                since their penetration increases continuously. This speech will first discuss the
                                mathematical formulation derivation of the exact aggregated feasible region of
                                multiple DERs. Then, this speech will talk about the exact mathematical expression of
                                aggregate temporally coupled power flexibility of DERs considering linear distribution
                                system security constraints. An approximate model is built to reduce the complexity,
                                which can be used for practical applications. Lastly, to illustrate the dispatch of large-
                                scale DERs, a transmission system economic dispatch model is developed considering
                                the power flexibility of distribution systems.





                                                                 Invited Speakers     Macau, China
                                                                 Keng Weng LAO


                                                                 Assistant Professor
                                                                 University of Macau


                                Research on Emerging Threats and Protection
                                Techniques of Energy IoT Cyber-physical System


                                The intenet of things technology is reshaping the energy system under 4th industrial
                                revolution, especially on the coupling between the cyber and physical world. While
                                the new technology brings about different advantages to the energy system, it also
                                causes a lot of emerging challenges such as new threats caused by cyber attack
                                and system uncertainties. In this talk, relevant reserach trend and studies are shared,
                                including risk evaluation, major treats and key protection techqniques. Example
                                studies such as challenges in protection of energy system against data loss/attack,
                                actions of energy system against extreme weather, will be discussed, and prelimiary
                                results obtained will be presented.]]></page><page Index="35"><![CDATA[2022


           Invited Speakers    Fisciano (SA), Italy
           Pierluigi SIANO                                                                                          Smart Energy Track   •  32


           Professor
           University of Salerno



           Optimization of Smart Energy Communities

           In the context of the energy transition, energy communities are gaining increasing
           attention all over the world, in recent years. By participating in an energy community,
           prosumers may take a leading role in the energy transition and improve the self-
           consumption of renewable energy produced inside the community. Prosumers can
           carry out energy exchanges inside the energy community and provide ancillary
           services to the system operators, thus contributing to improve the efficiency and
           stability of the grid.
           A novel scalable, privacy-preserving, and real-time distributed parallel optimization
           is proposed to manage a large-scale energy community, considering energy
           exchanges inside the community according to the model of virtual self-consumption
           and the provision of ancillary services. The proposed method preserves the privacy
           of prosumers and allows the assessment of the impact of energy exchanges on the
           ancillary services provided by an energy community. Simulation results confirmed
           that the proposed method is superior in terms of privacy if compared with the
           equivalent centralized optimization and that it has a convergence rate higher than
           that of the splitting conic solver (SCS).






           Invited Speakers     Guangdong, China
           Qiuwei WU


            Associate Professor
            Tsinghua University (Shenzhen)


           Decentralized/Distributed Optimal Operation of Power
           System with High Penetration of Renewables


           Environmental concerns and the quest for energy supply independence have
           resulted in increasing penetration of renewable energy sources (RESs) and a move
           toward electrification of transportation and heating. The fluctuation and uncertainty
           of renewable generation put a lot of stress on the economic and secure operation of
           the power system. In the meantime, the integration of distributed energy resources
           (DERs), including renewable distributed generation, flexible demands such as electric
           vehicles and heat pumps, and storage, brings both challenges and opportunities
           to the secure and cost-efficient operation of power systems with renewables. This
           talk will cover the concept of the smart grid and smart energy system, and discuss
           the details of decentralized congestion management, distributed voltage control
           and self-healing of active distribution networks. Moreover, the optimal operation
           of district energy systems will be presented which utilizes the interaction between
           energy sectors to improve the operation efficiency of active distribution networks.
           The distributed control of wind power will also be introduced which is to make the
           wind power more controllable and grid friendly.]]></page><page Index="36"><![CDATA[2022


                                                                 Invited Speakers    Singapore
                                                                 Yan XU


                                                                 Associate Professor
                                                                 Nanyang Technological University


                                Coordinated Operation and Planning of Distributed
       Smart Energy Track    •  33
                                Energy Resources (DERs) in Microgrids

                                Microgrid is an enabling technique for a Smart City to integrate distributed energy
                                resources (DERs) such as distributed generation, energy storage, flexible loads, etc.
                                In Singapore, the Nanyang Technological University (NTU) is leading a Microgrid
                                demonstration project called Renewable Energy Integration Demonstrator for
                                Singapore (REIDS) in Semakau Island, where multiple sub-microgrids are built and
                                owned by different industry partners. This seminar will firstly introduce the REIDS
                                project, and then present a series of methodologies by Dr Xu’s group for coordinated
                                operation and planning of the DERs among different temporal and spatial scales.







                                                                 Invited Speakers    Shanghai, China
                                                                 Miao ZHU

                                                                 Professor
                                                                 Shanghai JiaoTong University


                                New Concept and Research Development of
                                Power Electronics Equipment for DC System

                                As the deployment of renewable energy sources (RES) grows rapidly and the power
                                electronics technologies advance considerably in recent years, the direct current
                                (DC) has come back into the modern power systems with a completely new look.
                                This lecture will center upon the requirements for modern power systems to meet
                                the challenge of ever-increasing RES penetration level, with a focus on the basic
                                concepts of various state-of-the-art DC equipment. Topics on several latest multi-
                                terminal DC power transformers, DC power flow controllers, and their applications to
                                the DC systems, will be covered. As DC power conversion equipment will be the core
                                and foundation of future DC power grids, their designs based on specific application
                                scenarios are vital to satisfy the needs of different nodes within the DC grid. This
                                lecture will help to gain an in-depth understanding of the technical framework of the
                                DC system with advanced DC electrical equipment, and is suitable for researchers
                                and engineers working in the related fields.]]></page><page Index="37"><![CDATA[2022


           Invited Speakers    Paso, US
           Ruimin KE

           Assistant Professor
           University of Texas at El Paso                                                                           Intelligent Transportation Track    •  34


           Real-time Traffic and Road Surveillance
           with Parallel Edge Intelligence


           Edge computing, which is an emerging concept to complement cloud computing,
           processes data closer to where the data is generated at the network edge.
           Transportation system is a critical component of our cities and is generating more
           and more data. To leverage the power of the increasing amount of data from traffic
           sensors, researchers have started exploring the feasibility of edge computing for
           traffic big data analytics. Given the resource constraints on edge devices, it is very
           challenging to achieve high intelligence and real-time capability at the same time.
           There are few edge transportation systems that function in a multi-tasking mode
           with high efficiency and intelligence on the edge. In this talk, we introduce a multi-
           thread parallel edge system architecture and several lightweight algorithms for traffic
           and road surveillance. The designs ensure robustness and real-time capability for the
           key modules of the system.







           Invited Speakers     Cambridge, UK
           Zhe LIU


           Associate Professor
           Shanghai Jiao Tong University



           Cooperative Path Planning of Large-scale
           Mobile Robot Groups

           In recent years, large-scale mobile robot groups (hundreds or even thousands) have
           been implemented in the applications of unmanned warehousing and logistics,
           intelligent ports and self-driving scenarios, and have attracted increasing research
           interests from both the academic and industrial communities. Cooperative path
           planning is one of the most fundamental problems for large-scale mobile robot
           groups. How to achieve efficient and collision-free path planning of thousand-robot
           teams, and in the meantime, achieving robustness to communication and motion
           uncertainties, are the most challenging issues in real applications. In this presentation,
           the speaker will report his work on the topic of cooperative path planning of
           large-scale mobile robot groups, including hierarchical path planning and motion
           coordination framework, integrated optimization approach of task assignment and
           path planning, and robust planning strategy in the presence of communication and
           motion uncertainties. In addition,  the speaker will also report some extension works
           on the reinforcement learning enhanced approaches for multi-robot autonomous
           navigation.]]></page><page Index="38"><![CDATA[2022


                                                                Invited Speakers    Hong Kong, China
                                                                Jieming SHI


                                                                Assistant Professor
                                                                The Hong Kong Polytechnic University



                                Effective Network Embedding Methods
                                on Large-scale Graphs

                                Graph data are everywhere and important in many industrial applications, such
                                as social network recommendation. To support the urgent needs from real-world
                                applications, there are many Network Embedding methods developed in recent
       Intelligent Transportation Track    •   35
                                years. However, there is still a crucial challenge largely remaining unsolved: graphs
                                are growing with large volume, usually with hundreds of millions or billions of nodes
                                and edges, making current methods inefficient to handle such large-scale data.
                                It is infeasible to put unlimited computation resources and wait for long time to
                                get high-quality embedding results. We aim to develop new network embedding
                                methods that can handle large-scale graph data with limited resources, and still
                                achieve state-of-the-art quality. In this talk, we will introduce our recent network
                                embedding studies on homogeneous graphs, attributed graphs.






                                                                Invited Speakers     Beijing, China
                                                                Jingyuan WANG


                                                                 Professor
                                                                Beihang University


                                LibCity: An Open-source Platform for
                                Urban Spatio-temporal Prediction


                                In recent years, there has been a gradual increase in research related to traffic
                                prediction. However, the lack of a unified framework for evaluating experiments
                                makes it difficult to determine whether the performance improvement of traffic
                                prediction models is a genuine technical advancement or caused by tuning
                                techniques or dataset differences. To address this problem, we propose LibCity, a
                                scalable, unified open-source traffic prediction evaluation platform that provides
                                researchers with a credible tool for comparative experiments and a convenient tool
                                for model development. In LibCity, we currently cover 9 traffic prediction tasks, 65
                                baseline models and integrate 35 spatiotemporal datasets for researchers to conduct
                                comprehensive evaluation experiments. In addition, researchers can easily develop
                                new models based on LibCity, which means that researchers can easily compare new
                                models with models reproduced in the library. Thanks to this, LibCity will significantly
                                contribute to the standardization and rapid development of the field of traffic
                                prediction. LibCity has been open-sourced on GitHub and has been used in practice
                                by more than 50 organizations worldwide, receiving 400+ stars. In this talk, we will
                                introduce the LibCity open-source platform.]]></page><page Index="39"><![CDATA[2022

           Invited Speakers    Macau, China
           Ye WANG


           Assistant Professor
           University of Macau                                                                                      Intelligent Transportation Track    •  36


           The Real Impact and the User Perception of
           Sandwich Attacks in the DeFi Ecosystem

           Decentralized finance (DeFi) enables crypto-asset holders to conduct complex
           financial transactions, while maintaining control over their assets in the blockchain
           ecosystem. However, the transparency of blockchain networks and the open
           mechanism of DeFi applications also cause new security issues. In this talk, we focus
           on sandwich attacks, where attackers take advantage of the transaction confirmation
           delay and cause financial losses for victims. We evaluate the impact and investigate
           users' perceptions of sandwich attacks through a mix-method study. We find that
           due to users' lack of technical background and insufficient notifications from the
           markets, many users were not aware of the existence and the impact of sandwich
           attacks. They also had a limited understanding of how to resolve the security issue.
           Interestingly, users showed high tolerance for the impact of sandwich attacks on
           individuals and the ecosystem, despite potential financial losses. We discuss general
           implications for users, DeFi applications, and the community.





           Invited Speakers     Hong Kong, China
           Huan YIN


           Research Assistant Professor
           The Hong Kong University of
           Science and Technology


           Robust and Efficient Mobile Robot
           Localization Using LiDAR and Radar

           Localization is a fundamental module in autonomous navigation system. In recent
           years, mobile robots are delpoyed in large-scale and complex environments, and a
           robust and efficient mobile robot localization is desired for long-term autonomy. In
           this talk, we will discuss how to build a robust and efficient robot localization using
           two range sensors: LiDAR and Radar. Specifically, we will introduce a LiDAR map
           compression framework and a novel Radar localization on LiDAR maps. In addition,
           this talk will also discuss about new trends and emerging techniques for robotic
           mapping (SLAM) and localization.]]></page><page Index="40"><![CDATA[2022

                                                                 Invited Speakers    Beijing, China
                                                                Baochang ZHANG


                                                                 Professor
                                                                 Beihang University



                                Decoupling Causal Learning Method and Applications

                                Deep learning has been successfully applied in solving practical problems, but
                                its model parameters are highly coupled, which affects the optimization and
                                generalization of the model. In order to solve these issues, a decoupling causal
       Intelligent Transportation Track    •  37
                                learning method is proposed. Based on the decoupling of causal relationship and
                                parameters, a reliable causal relationship of the model is realized, so as to improve
                                the reliability and robustness of the machine learning method. In implantation, a
                                CoGradient descent algorithm is proposed for decoupling causal learning by taking
                                bilinear model as an example. In order to improve the effectiveness of the model, a
                                series of model compression methods are introduced to improve the model capacity
                                and generalization ability while reducing the complexity of the model. Related
                                applications include: 1-bit model compression, object detection and associative
                                learning.






                                                                Invited Speakers     Beijing, China
                                                                Kuangyu ZHENG


                                                                 Associate Professor
                                                                Beihang University


                                Towards Smart and Energy-efficient
                                UAV Systems and Applications

                                Unmanned Aerial Vehicles (UAVs), with their outstanding flexibility and rapid
                                response capability, are increasingly used in varies scenarios for smart cities and wild
                                areas, such as IoT data collection, emergency communication, package delivery,
                                disaster relief, intelligent agriculture, etc. However, limited energy supply has become
                                a bottle neck for UAVs. In this talk, we will introduce several of our latest UAV studies
                                on joint optimization with speed, trajectory and applications, towards their best
                                energy efficiency.]]></page><page Index="41"><![CDATA[2022

           Invited Speakers    Guangzhou, China
           Meixin ZHU


            Assistant Professor
           The Hong Kong University of Science and Technology (Guangzhou)                                           Intelligent Transportation Track    •  38



           Learning Realistic and Reactive Traffic Agents


            Microscopic traffic simulation has been studied for decades in the transportation
            engineering field. However, bridging the behavior gap between the simulated and
            actual worlds remains to be a challenge. This talk presents a learning-based method
            for traffic agent simulation. This learning-based method facilitates two important
            properties of traffic simulation for autonomous vehicle (AV) development: realistic
            and reactive, where the former means simulated agents’ behavior should match
            log-replayed ones in standard conditions, and the latter means simulated agents
            should react to the behavioral variations of AVs and other agents in the same way
            drivers would do on the road. To achieve this, we learn data-driven agents model
            in an end-to-end fashion based on real-world driving data with detailed interaction
            information and high-definition maps (HD Maps). For each agent in a driving
            scenario, we build an agent-centric multi-channel image to capture its current and
            historical interactions with other agents, road elements, and traffic control devices. A
            convolutional neural network is then used to extract features from the raster image
            and predict the agent's future trajectory through supervised learning. The observed
            future 6-second trajectory with a 2 Hz sampling rate is used for training. At inference
            time, we do closed-loop simulation by looping between updating agents' positions
            and orientations with the predictions from the agent model and generating new
            predictions based on updated simulation states. We train and evaluate our models
            with hundreds of hours of real-world driving data collected by a fleet of level-5
            AVs. Results show that the learned models can simulate diverse and realistic traffic
            behavior in a reactive way.]]></page><page Index="42"><![CDATA[2022

                                                                 Invited Speakers    Coventry, UK
                                                                Xueyu GENG


                                                                 Reader
                                                                 The University of Warwick



                                Susceptibility Analysis and Economic Vulnerability
                                of Buildings to Glacier-related Debris Flows

                                Gyirong serves as an important channel to Chine-Nepal Economic Corridor, but
                                it suffers from severe glacier-related debris flows every year. In order to form a
                                debris-flow mitigation strategy, a susceptibility map in response to precipitation
                                and temperature change is urgent. Additionally, the estimation of the economic
                                vulnerability of building at risk is also essential since vulnerability is the key
                                component of quantitative risk assessment. Therefore, in this presentation, a hybrid
                                machine learning model, certainty factor - genetic algorithm - support vector
                                classification (CF-GA-SVM), will be introduced firstly to map the catchment-based
                                susceptibility of glacier-related debris flows. Eleven causative factors were selected to
       Urban Public Safety and Disaster Prevention Track    •  39
                                generate a susceptibility map. The receiver operating characteristics curve (ROC) and
                                prediction accuracy (ACC) were used to evaluate the model performance. Then, the
                                catchments with high susceptibility levels were extracted to predict the economic
                                vulnerability (Ve) of buildings to future glacier-related debris flows. The economic
                                vulnerability relies on the calculation of impact pressure to buildings, and the impact
                                pressure is decided based on the predicted debris-flow volume by using a machine
                                learning algorithm, XGBoost. A total of 60 debris-flow events were identified to train
                                and test the prediction model based on the selection of four geomorphic factors.
                                The prediction results were validated by Mean Absolute Percentage Error (MAPE). The
                                studies showed that the CF-GA-SVM model achieved AUC (Area Under Curve) of 0.945
                                and ACC of 0.800, respectively. The maximum impact pressure on buildings by future
                                glacier-related debris flows reached 67.3kPa and the lowest impact pressure was
                                only 6.3kPa. As for the economic vulnerability of buildings, the maximum economic
                                vulnerability was found to be 143.41 €/m2 and the minimum value lowered to 0.19 €/
                                m2.]]></page><page Index="43"><![CDATA[2022


           Invited Speakers    Hangzhou, China
           Zhiguo HE


           Professor
           Zhejiang University


            Fast and Maneuverable Soft Robots
            Driven by Underwater Combustion                                                                         Urban Public Safety and Disaster Prevention Track    •  40

           Exploration in complicated and unpredictable underwater environments, especially
           deep sea, require highly flexible and adjustable devices. Soft robots have been
           extensively reported in many fields, and provide a possible option due to their
           potential to be fast, accurate and tunable for multifunctional applications. However,
           the implementation of their rapid turn and acceleration underwater is still a
           challenge. This leads to an urgent need for rapid response with good controllability,
           especially for those underwater applications. In this study, we develop, and
           quantitatively assess, combustion-driven soft robots with programmable underwater
           locomotion. The soft robots are designed with gas chambers that are inflated
           with oxygen-to-propane mixed gas and sealed by ultra-expandable silicon rubber
           membranes. Combustion of the mixed gas expands the membranes to propel
           water. Adjusting the location and amount of gas for combustion, the soft robots
           demonstrate programmable motions. The kinematic performance of the soft robot
           can achieve 1.2 body length in 300 ms. The acceleration and performance of the soft
           robots are confirmed by our experimental measurements, theoretical analyses, and
           numerical simulations.






            Invited Speakers    Cardiff, UK
            Shunqi PAN


            Professor
            Cardiff University



           The Impact of the Climate Change and
           Sea Level Rise on the UK Coasts

            The coastal regions are under increasing threats from the global climate change.
            This talk will highlight the updated results of the global climate change research and
            the UK climate projections published in 2018, particularly the sea level rise around
            the UK coasts. It will also present the model applications of the flood risk along the
            Welsh coast under the sea level rise scenarios using the advanced TELEMAC suite.
            Flood dynamics and the flood hazard rating in a number of flood-prone areas are
            illustrated.]]></page><page Index="44"><![CDATA[2022

                                                                 Invited Speakers    Chengdu, China
                                                                 Dalei PENG


                                                                 Associate Professor
                                                                 State Key Laboratory of Geohazard Prevention and
                                                                 Geoenvironment Protection, Chengdu University of Technology


                                Successful Implementations of a Real-time
                                and Intelligent Early Warning System for Loess
                                Landslides on the Heifangtai Terrace

                                Real-time monitoring and intelligent early warning system are crucial and significant
                                to take mitigation measures and reduce casualties and property losses related
                                to landslides. It is difficult to obtain entire monitoring data in the accelerated
                                deformation phase in a landslide event, and hard to issue early warning information
                                using a traditional monitoring approach with fixed and low sampling frequency.
                                Displacement increments of loess landslides induced by agriculture irrigation on
                                the Heifangtai terrace could be sudden and extremely rapid. Typical landslide types
                                include loess flowslides and loess falls. It is of practical significance to develop a self-
       Urban Public Safety and Disaster Prevention Track    •  41
                                adaptive data acquisition monitoring technique and establish a real-time landslide
                                early warning system (LEWS) to meet the needs for risk mitigation of rapid sliding
                                slopes on the Heifangtai terrace. The monitoring technique can wirelessly transmit
                                displacement data and the LEWS was devised using the new artificial intelligence.
                                The LEWS could automatically release the warning information in advance of the
                                event once the early warning parameters exceed default thresholds. In this study,
                                the early warning procedures, real-time monitoring approach, intelligent LEWS,
                                a multiple criteria warning model, warning release and emergency mitigation
                                measures, and performance are introduced in detail. Six loess landslides at Heifangtai
                                and eight landslides in other regions of China have been successfully warned since
                                its implementation in 2012. This study proposed an effective and practical solution
                                for the early warning of loess landslides at Heifangtai. Two typical loess landslides
                                that had successful early warnings at Heifangtai were presented. The successful
                                implementation could serve as a reference for global rapid slope failure cases,
                                considering the complex nature of landslide behaviors and failure mechanisms.]]></page><page Index="45"><![CDATA[2022


            Invited Speakers    Zhuhai, China
           Chunhua QIU


            Professor
 State Key Laboratory of Geohazard Prevention and
 Geoenvironment Protection, Chengdu University of Technology  Sun Yat-Sen University


           Case Study of Oceanic Response to Tropical Cyclone

           Tropical cyclones(TCs) can induce sea surface cooling, freshening, and phytoplankton                     Urban Public Safety and Disaster Prevention Track    •  42
           blooms. By using automatic unman vehicles (AUVs), we investigate the responses of
           sea surface temperature, and the dissolved oxygen (DO) concentration to TCs within
           an anticyclone in the northern South China Sea. DO concentrations have a higher
           value at the edge of eddy than at the core. Influenced by TC, DO concentrations
           decrease remarkably in the subsurface layer in all three regions (inside, edge, and
           outside of the anticyclonic eddy). The mean DO concentrations decrease more at the
           edge of the anticyclone than those inside the anticyclone. The recovery time of DO
           concentration after TC is around one week at the edge of the anticyclone and is >10
           days within the eddy. Our observations show that the DO concentrations decrease
           above the subsurface chlorophyll a maxima layer. Quantitative analysis shows that
           variations in DO concentration are dominated by horizontal advection and vertical
           advection terms in the subsurface layer.




           Invited Speakers    Beijing, China
           Qiuhong TANG


           Professor
           Institute of Geographic Sciences and Natural Resources Research,
           Chinese Academy of Sciences


           Adaptive Reservoir Management under Climate
           Change in the Lancang-Mekong River Basin

           Hydropower dams are proliferating in the riparian countries of the Lancang-Mekong
           River Basin (LMRB) driven by the pursuit of renewable electricity and societal
           resilience to flooding. However, the tradeoffs between hydropower production and
           flood control are unclear in a changing environment. In this study, a reservoir module
           was incorporated into the Variable Infiltration Capacity (VIC) hydrological model to
           simulate the streamflow susceptible to the reservoirs in the Lancang-Mekong River
           basin, and to quantify the relative effects of climate change and reservoir operation
           on flood and hydropower generation. Results show that climate change would
           increase flood magnitude and frequency. Reservoirs can be managed to mitigate
           the risks of hydrological extreme events, and help achieve Goal 13 SDG in the river
           basin. Adaptive reservoir regulation comes with a cost of hydropower generation,
           suggesting the importance of coordinating water and energy management across
           countries in the transboundary river basin.]]></page><page Index="46"><![CDATA[2022


                                                                Invited Speakers    Zhuhai, China
                                                                Dongxiao WANG


                                                                Professor
                                                                Sun Yat-Sen University



                                Marine Observation Strategy for the
                                Tropical Coastal Cities‘ SDG 14

                                To provide long-term field observation and strengthen the ability of marine disaster
                                prevention and mitigation, it is urgently needed to build a fully integrated island-
                                based marine ecosystem research station. To this aim, Pearl River Estuary Marine
                                Ecosystem Research Station, Ministry of Education, has been established since 2019.
                                This station is a sustainable observation system integrating unmanned observation
                                platforms to provide physical oceanography and marine environment data in coastal
                                cities in Guangdong-Hong Kong-Macao Greater Bay Area (GBA). Based on the long-
                                term data of a buoy deployed at Jitimen in Pearl River Estuary (PRE), we analyzed the
                                dynamical and thermodynamic responses of the ocean waters to typhoons Cempaka
       Urban Public Safety and Disaster Prevention Track    •  43
                                and Lubit passage. Additionally, Indo-Pacific Humpback Dolphins habitat selection
                                and its response to the complex and changeable estuarine dynamic process in the
                                PRE were explored based on the automated acoustic monitoring at the buoy and
                                ship-based acoustic monitoring, which provides a valuable scientific basis for the
                                marine environment management. Lastly, an innovative platform for long-term
                                coastal morphodynamics observation was set up to provide important support
                                for wetland restoration and coastal protection. Overall, the integrated observation
                                strategy of the Pearl River Estuary Marine Ecosystem Research Station is expected
                                to serve the conservation and sustainably usage of the oceans, seas and marine
                                resources for sustainable development in the GBA.]]></page><page Index="47"><![CDATA[2022


            Invited Speakers    Macau, China
            Wangji YAN


            Associate Professor
            University of Macau


           Accounting for Multiple Uncertainties in the Digital
           Twinning of Structural Dynamical Systems Based on                                                        Urban Public Safety and Disaster Prevention Track    •  44
           Fast Bayesian Learning and Metamodeling

            Dynamic model updating with evolving monitoring data have been viewed as a
            starting point and a key functionality of the digital twining for structural systems.
            This study aims at developing a key part of digital twin technology by making full
            use of the Bayesian model updating to account for multiple uncertainties such as
            measurement noise and model error properly. Bayesian nonparametric modelling
            technique that provides a surrogate mapping between the probability spaces of the
            model parameters and the theoretical responses are employed to replace a large
            number of time-consuming finite element simulations required in the likelihood
            evaluations by very fast approximate estimates. The transitional Monte Carlo Markov
            Chain in conjunction with the metamodel is used to sample the posterior probability
            density function of the updated parameters at a very reasonable cost. Furthermore,
            a distributed parallel computing scheme was utilized to allow the TMCMC stochastic
            simulation to run across multiple CPU cores. Several case studies with field test data
            are used to verify the accuracy and efficiency of the proposed algorithm. Results
            indicate that the fast-numerical strategies proposed in this study can exploit the
            availability of high-performance computing facilities to improve the computational
            efficiency and reduce the time-to-solution in developing the critical part of the
            digital twin for large-scale dynamical systems.






           Invited Speakers    Liverpool, UK
           Yan ZHOU


           Lecturer
           University of Liverpool


           Two-phase Modelling of Sediment
           Transport by Incompressible SPH


           Sediment transport has been broadly modelled from the conventional convection-
           diffusion equation to sophisticated individual grain tracking method with various
           demands of empirical coefficients and computational resources. This study develops
           a new two-phase Lagrangian model under the framework of ISPH for sediment
           movement which is fully coupled with the flow through inter- and intra-phase
           interactions. The incompressible scheme enables stable fluid pressure simulation
           by implicitly solving fluid pressure Poisson equation. The model will be validated
           by static neutral buoyant case for testing the stability, sediment settling against
           analytical solution and sand dumping for testing complex flow and sediment
           concentration fields development.]]></page><page Index="48"><![CDATA[2022

                                                                 Invited Speakers    Hong Kong, China
                                                                Songye ZHU


                                                                Professor
                                                                The Hong Kong Polytechnic University



                                SMA-based Seismic-Resistant Structures: From
                                Smart <aterials to resilient structures

                                Traditional seismic design philosophy attempts to concentrate permanent damage
                                in selected “sacrificial” regions after earthquakes. However, damaged buildings are
                                often demolished after earthquakes because too large residual deformation makes
                                repair economically unviable. As a high-performance metallic material, superelastic
                                shape memory alloys (SMAs) are appealing to the earthquake engineering
                                community because their flag-shaped hysteresis can minimize post-earthquake
                                residual deformation and enhance structural repairability. This presentation will
                                highlight the research on seismic applications of superelastic SMAs, from material,
                                structural member, to structural system levels. The results show superelastic SMAs
       Urban Public Safety and Disaster Prevention Track    •  45
                                can provide a promising solution to high-performance resilient structural systems.]]></page><page Index="49"><![CDATA[2022








 The Hong Kong Polytechnic University

           Open Research Project






           Highlight Session]]></page><page Index="50"><![CDATA[2022



                                                                 Invited Speakers    Shenzhen, China
                                                                 Suzhi BI


                                                                 Associate Professor
                                                                 Shenzhen University


                                Federated Transfer Learning for Domain-
                                Adaptive Indoor Wireless Sensing

                                Wireless indoor sensing that leverages the rich scattering environment can provide
                                various context-related sensing functions, such as crowd, posture and respiration
                                monitoring. The key technical problem is that the sensing accuracy is heavily
                                dependent on the environment, where a well-functioning model finetuned to one
                                domain may perform poorly in another unfamiliar one, even under minor change of
       Open Research Project Highlight Session    •  47
                                background setting or transceiver placement. In this joint work between Shenzhen
                                University and University of Macau, we propose potential solutions using transfer and
                                federated learning techniques, combined with sensing data processing methods, to
                                achieve domain-adaptive and sample-efficient sensing performance across dissimilar
                                environments.





                                                                 Invited Speakers    Beijing, China
                                                                 Tinghai CHENG


                                                                 Researcher
                                                                 Beijing Institute of Nanoenergy and Nanosystem,
                                                                 Chinese Academy of Sciences


                                Development and Applications of Triboelectric
                                Sensors in the Industrial Technology

                                Self-powered sensing technologies is inevitable to the develop of smart machinery.
                                Herein, a series of self-powered mechanical motion sensors based on triboelectric
                                nanogenerator are proposed for the linear or rotary motion measurement. And
                                the triboelectric flow sensors with a built-in float structure are invented for the
                                fluid measurement. In addition, the vibration sensor based on the double-spring-
                                piece structure, as is one of the widely applied sensing technologies, is proposed.
                                These researches can effectively promote the development and applications of self-
                                powered sensing technology.]]></page><page Index="51"><![CDATA[2022


           Invited Speakers    Xiamen, China
           Liqun FU


           Professor
           Xiamen University                                                                                        Open Research Project Highlight Session    •  48


           Joint MCS Adaptation and RB Allocation in Cellular
           Networks Based on Deep Reinforcement
           Learning with Stable Matching

           Joint modulation-coding scheme (MCS) adaptation and resource block (RB)
           allocation is an effective approach to guarantee different quality of service (QoS)
           requirements of all UEs under dynamic network environments. We put forth an
           online learning technique, referred to as integrated Deep Reinforcement learning and
           stable Matching (DeepRM), in the sense that the MCS adaptation and RB allocation
           decisions are conducted without acquiring the real-time channel quality indicator
           (CQI) feedback. DeepRM is a closed-loop framework, where the output of deep
           reinforcement learning (DRL) is imported into the stable matching to guide optimal
           RB allocation whilst the output of stable matching is fed into the DRL framework to
           assist efficient MCS decision-making.  Simulation results demonstrate that compared
           with ACO-HM, OLLA-ADA, and ARBDQ-Random algorithms, DeepRM induces much
           less RB consumption while guaranteeing the QoS requirements of all UEs in various
           network scenarios. Furthermore, DeepRM is more robust than other baselines.





           Invited Speakers    Hong Kong, China
           Zhenyu YIN

           Professor
           The Hong Kong Polytechnic University



           Practice of Machine Learning in
           Constitutive Modelling of Soils

           There is significant potential for machine learning (ML) to achieve step-change
           advances in the state-of-the-art for constitutive modelling of geomaterials.
           However, a common challenge and criticism of ML for geotechnical modelling is
           a lack of interpretability and onerous dependency on big data. This study presents
           an interpretable data-driven constitutive modelling approach for application in
           the context of sparse geotechnical data. Improved interpretability is achieved by
           incorporating (a) ‘multi-fidelity’ strategy, (b) physics constraints and (c) uncertainty
           within the predictions.]]></page><page Index="52"><![CDATA[2022



                                                                 Invited Speakers    Guangzhou, China
                                                                 Junbo ZHANG

                                                                 Professor
                                                                 South China University of Technology



                                Challenges of Digitizing Power Grid Operation
                                Business and a Brief Discussion on the Bottleneck
                                of the Digital Platform’s Data Lake

                                The digitization of operation business is the core for constructing a digital power
                                grid. Presently, the modularized and platformized flexible construction for massive
                                applications faces a bottleneck of data lake. Therefore, we propose a short-term
       Open Research Project Highlight Session    •  49
                                solution for the bottleneck by combining conceptualism and empiricism. The
                                proposed method can be verified in the key technology project of China Southern
                                Power Grid “Research and Application of Key Technologies of Online Intelligent
                                Analysis System for Frequency Stability of Large Power Grids”. Meanwhile, long-
                                term solution methods are carried out, including the flexible organization method
                                of power grid heterogeneous data, distributed software data link modeling and
                                analysis method, massive link monitoring and dispatching technology, etc. Thereby,
                                the practical difficulties faced by the digitization of power grid operation business are
                                hopeful to be completely solved in the near future. The ecological development of
                                digital power grids with more collaboration, participation and common interests will
                                be promoted.]]></page><page Index="53"><![CDATA[2022










 South China University of Technology
           Industrial









           Session]]></page><page Index="54"><![CDATA[2022









                                                         Industrial Session     Huawei

                                                         Hugo Yuan
       Industrial Session    •  51


                                                          Huawei Senior Solution Manager



                     Talk Title
                     Digital Technology Supports the Smart Grid Construction

                     in Guangdong-Hong Kong-Macao Greater Bay Area













                                                         Industrial Session     CEM, S.A

                                                         Charles LEONG


                                                          Information System Department Technical Advisor
                                                          Secretory of Innovation and Technology Committee of CEM
                                                          Companhia de Electricidade de Macau - CEM, S.A.

                     Talk Title
                     CEM Advanced Metering Infrastructure (AMI) Development















                                                         Industrial Session     Zhen Wua Harbour Construction
                                                         Yang QIAO


                                                          Deputy Director
                                                          Zhen Hwa Harbour Construction Co., Ltd.


                     Talk Title
                     A More Liveable City – The Smart City Practice as a Chinese

                     Infrastructure Provider]]></page><page Index="55"><![CDATA[2022









          Poster









          Session]]></page><page Index="56"><![CDATA[2022
                    Authors                    Affiliation                           Poster Title

                                     Institute of Geographic Sciences
                                     and Natural Resources Research,
             Chaodong Zhou, Qiuhong
            Tang, Hengxing Lan, Roland   Chinese Academy of Sciences;   Ground deformation monitoring and mechanism
              Bürgmann, Timothy A.   University of Chinese Academy of   analysis by satellite InSAR and geophysics model in
       Poster Session    •  53
                    Warner           Sciences;  Chang’anUniversity;              Yan’an New District
                                     University of California, Berkeley;
                                         West Virginia University;

              Cong Tang, Shuyu He,        University of Macau          Settlement-based framework for long-term
                 Wanhuan Zhou                                         serviceability assessment of immersed tunnels

            Daoyuan Tan, Shaoqun Lin,                               Development of a monitoring and warning system
                                       The Hong Kong Polytechnic
             Peichen Wu, Sinchi Kuok,                              based on optical fiber sensing technology for masonry
                                      University; University of Macau
                   Jianhua Yin                                                 retaining walls and trees
                                                                   Intelligent Modeling and Optimization of Smart Energy
                Dongdong Zhang             Guangxi University     System Considering Flexible Two-Dimensional Demand
                                                                                     Response

                                                                   Data-driven nonparameteric optimization method for
                    Ge Chen               University of Macau
                                                                                  power scheduling

              Guoliang Qiu, Yanheng   Shanghai Jiao Tong University;   A Perfect Sampler for Hypergraph Independent Sets
               Wang, Chihao Zhang    University of Macau; ETH Zürich

                                                                   Behavior-aware Trajectory Prediction for  Autonomous
            Haicheng Liao, Zhenning Li    University of Macau
                                                                                       Driving

                                                                      The Propagation and Interaction of Tide, River
                  Haoxuan Du              University of Macau
                                                                     Discharge, and Storm Surge in Coastal Channels

                                                                  Modeling the Super Typhoon Mangkhut (2018) Intensity
            Hong Wang, Liang Gao, Lei   University of Macau; Sun Yat-sen
                      Zhu                      University            Changes under Warmer Sea Surface Temperature
                                                                                     Scenarios
                                                                   Decentralized Energy Management of Microgrid Based
                   Hongyi Li              University of Macau      on Blockchain-empowered Consensus Algorithm with
                                                                                 Collusion Prevention
            Huawei Hou , Suzhi Bi1 , Lili
             Zheng, Xiaohui Lin, Yuan   Shenzhen University; University of  DASECount: Domain-Agnostic Sample-Efficient Wireless
                Wu, and Zhi Quan                Macau                 Indoor Crowd Counting via Few-shot Learning
                                                                     Bayesian Updating for High-fidelity Vehicle-Track
                 Jiangzheng zhan          University of Macau      Coupled Dynamical System based on Wheel-rail Force
                                                                                 Field Measurements
              Jiawei Zhu, Zhuangtong
             Huang, Yixin Xu,  Jerome     University of Macau           Data Privacy Protection in DeFi Protocols
                  Yen, Ye Wang
                                                                   Challenges of digitizing power grid operation business
                                        South China University of
              Junbo Zhang, Junye Li                                and a brief discussion on the bottleneck of the digital
                                              Technology
                                                                                platform’s data lake
                                                                   Accurate water level estimations at ungauged sites in a
            Kai Fei, Haoxuan Du, Liang    University of Macau      tidal reach: Symbiotic Integration of Physics-based and
                      Gao
                                                                             Machine Learning Approaches]]></page><page Index="57"><![CDATA[2022
                    Authors                    Affiliation                           Poster Title

                                                                  Design and Analysis of BTB-DC Electric Spring for Lower   Poster Session    •  54
               Li Liu, Jianhua Gong,
                                          University of Macau        Converter and Storage Device Rating considering
                 Kengweng Lao
                                                                         Impedance Ratio Impact in DC Microgrid
                                                                  Novel Machine Learning Techniques-assisted Intelligent
                  Linfeng Mei             University of Macau
                                                                       Structural Health Monitoring and Diagnosis

                                     Fujian Key Laboratory of Sensing
                 Longbiao Chen                                    Mobility Behavior Analytics from Urban Spatial Big Data
                                      and Computing for Smart City

                                                                     Enhancing Resilience of Integrated Electricity-Gas
                 Maosheng Sang             Zhejiang University
                                                                       Systems: A Skeleton-Network Based Strategy

                                                                   Variabilities of the Transport Structure in Estuary-shelf
                    Mingyu Li             University of Macau
                                                                          System from Lagrangian Perspective
                                                                      Decoupled Scheme for Interval Model Updating
                    Mo Jiang              University of Macau         assisted by HDMR and Chebyshev polynomial
                                                                                   approximation
             Mun On, Wong, Zhiqian   University of Macau; The University   "BIM and Multi-user AR Integrated Lift Operation
           Zhang, Yutong Qiao ,Manhin        of Hong Kong;               Coordination for Modular Construction"
            Ho, Wei Pan ,  Chichiu Lam
                                       University of Macau, Zhuhai
                                     University of Macau (UM) Science
                                    and Technology Research Institute,
                                      Qilu University of Technology,
                                     Shandong Academy of Sciences,
             Nanyang Chu, Guangliang   South China Sea Institute of
             Liu, Jie Xu, Peng Yao, Yan   Oceanology, Chinese Academy of   Hydrodynamical transport structure and lagrangian
             Du, Zhiqiang Liu, Zhongya   Sciences (CAS), Hohai University,   connectivity of circulations in the Pearl River Estuary
                      Cai            University of Chinese Academy of
                                    Sciences, Southern Marine Science
                                       and Engineering Guangdong
                                    Laboratory (Guangzhou), Southern
                                        University of Science and
                                              Technology

                                                                     Frequency Regulation Capacity Offering of District
             Peipei Yu, Hongcai Zhang,
                 Yonghua Song             University of Macau      Cooling System: An Intrinsic-motivated Reinforcement
                                                                                  Learning Method

                                        University of Macau, Hong     The response of vertical interplay in the layered
                  Qibang TANG         Kong University of Science and   circulation of South China Sea to the slope topography
                                              Technology                      and lateral exchanging flow

                                                                      Optimal operation of Soft Open Points in Active
                   Qilin Hou              University of Macau
                                                                                Distribution Networks
              Rufan Bai, Haoxing Lin,                                Mixed Strategies for Security Games with General
             Xinyu Yang, Xiaowei Wu,      University of Macau                  Defending Requirements
               Minming Li, Weijia Jia


            Shengwei Zhou, Xiaowei Wu     University of Macau        Approximate EFX Allocation for Indivisible Chores]]></page><page Index="58"><![CDATA[2022
                    Authors                    Affiliation                           Poster Title

                                                                  CrowdTelescope: Wi-Fi-Positioning-Based Multi-Grained
              Shiyu Zhang, Bangchao
                Deng, Dingqi Yang         University of Macau        Spatiotemporal Crowd Flow Prediction for Smart
                                                                                      Campus
                                                                    Research on the settlement prediction of immersed
            Shuyu He, Wanhuan Zhou,
       Poster Session    •  55
             Cong Tang , Sin Chi Kuok     University of Macau         tunnel based on the physics-informed machine
                                                                                      learning
             Su Qin, Tao Xu, Wanhuan      University of Macau;     Toward intelligent urban tunnel construction: real-time
                     Zhou                 Southeast University      prediction of pore-water pressure in front of a TBM

                                                                  An Influence Line-Free Bridge Weight-In-Motion Scheme
                 Tengteng Hao             University of Macau       for Monitoring Gross Vehicle Weight: Fundamental,
                                                                               Approach and Application

              Tianhe Ren, Liang Gao,   China University of Geosciences  Spatiotemporal prediction of rain-induced landslide
                 Wenping Gong                                        susceptibility using machine learning technology


                                                                   Intelligent Home Energy Management Strategy based
              Tianyun Xu, Tao Chen        Southeast University
                                                                       on Multi-agent Artificial Intelligence-of-Things
                                     Shandong University; ETH Zurich;
               Xiankai Lu, Wenguan    Inception Institute of Artifificial
            Wang, Jianbing Shen, David   Intelligence, UAE;  Indiana   Segmenting Objects from Relational Visual Data
              Crandall, Luc Van Gool
                                               University
            Yan Li, Wanhuan Zhou, Ping                                Flood risk assessment of artificial islands under
                     Shen                 University of Macau               compound rain-tide-wind effects

             Yan Wei, Shen Ping, Zhou                                  3D Subsurface Visualization with Uncertainty
                   Wen-Huan               University of Macau                 Quantification for Smart City

            Yunzhi Zhao, Xuefen Chi, Lei  University of Macau; Jilin University;   Resource Allocation and Slicing Puncture in Cellular
            Qian, Yuhong Zhu, Fen Hou      Tiangong University    Networks With eMBB and URLLC Terminals Coexistence

                                                                     Estimation of time-varying noise parameters for
                   Yusong Liu             University of Macau
                                                                                unscented Kalman filter

                                                                    Over-the-Air Computing Aided Federated Learning
             Zhenzhen Chen, Jingwen        Xiamen University;      and Analytics via Belief Propagation Based Stochastic
             Tong,  Liqun Fu, Zhu Han     University of Houston
                                                                                      Bandits

                   Zuntao Hu              University of Macau         "A fast and reliable optimal power flow solver"



            Zhiyong Cui, Meng-Ju Tsai,
              Meixin Zhu, Hao Yang,        Beihang University;     Traffic Performance Score 2.0: Measure Urban Mobility
             Chenxi Liu, Yinhai Wang    University of Washington         and Online Near-term Traffic Prediction

              Zhouquan Feng, Jiren   Key Laboratory for Wind and Bridge
            Zhang, Yafei Wang, Zhiwen   Engineering of Hunan Province,   Bayesian Approach for Damping Identification of Stay
            Liu, Xugang Hua, Zhengqing   Research Institute of Hunan   Cables with Ambient Vibration Measurements
                     Chen                University in Chongqing
                                                                     Key Technologies for Digital Twin-enabled Air-Sea
                    Zhou Su              Xi'an Jiaotong University
                                                                            Collaborative Marine Networks"]]></page><page Index="59"><![CDATA[2022











           Steering









           Committee]]></page><page Index="60"><![CDATA[2022


           Steering Committee










       Steering Committee   •   57















                Prof. Mark GIROLAMI                          Prof. Zhiquan (Tom) LUO
                 University of Cambridge             The Chinese University of Hong Kong (Shenzhen)

























                  Prof. Lionel M. NI                      Prof. Xuemin (Sherman) SHEN
               The Hong Kong University of                      University of Waterloo
           Scienceand Technology (Guangzhou)
























               Prof. Chengzhong XU                           Prof. Anthony G. O. YEH
                  University of Macau                        The University of Hong Kong]]></page><page Index="61"><![CDATA[2022











           Organizing









           Committee]]></page><page Index="62"><![CDATA[2022


                                Organizing Committee





                                General Chairs                                           Operation Chair





      Organizing Committee  •  59









                                    Prof. Yonghua SONG        Prof. Renzhong GUO               Prof. Shaodan MA
                                      Univerisity of Macau      Shenzhen University             Univerisity of Macau

                                Sensing and Communications Track Chairs
















                                       Prof. Fen HOU                Prof. Lin CAI              Prof.Ying WANG
                                      Univerisity of Macau      Illinois Institute of Technology  Beijing University of Post and Telecommunications


                                AI and Big Data Track Chairs
















                                     Prof. Jiantao ZHOU           Prof. Cong WANG                Prof. Yi CAI
                                      Univerisity of Macau      City University of Hong Kong  South China University of  Technology]]></page><page Index="63"><![CDATA[2022


           Smart Energy Track Chairs                                                                                Organizing Committee  •  60
















                 Prof. Ningyi DAI             Dr. Ying HUANG
                  Univerisity of Macau     Electric Power Research Institute
                                            China Southern Power Grid

           Smart Transportation Track Chairs
















                 Prof. Leong Hou U          Prof. Jingyuan WANG
                  Univerisity of Macau         Beihang University

           Urban Public Safety and Disaster Prevention Track Chairs

















               Prof. Wanhuan ZHOU             Dr Xueyu GENG             Prof. Dongxiao WANG
                  Univerisity of Macau       The University of Warwick    Sun Yat-Sen University


           Industrial Panel Session Chairs

















               Prof. Wanhuan ZHOU            Prof. Leong Hou U           Prof. Keng Weng LAO
                  Univerisity of Macau        Univerisity of Macau         Univerisity of Macau]]></page><page Index="64"><![CDATA[2022


                                Poster Session Chairs












      Organizing Committee  •  61



                                      Prof. Liang GAO            Prof. Hongcai ZHANG              Prof. Lei ZHU
                                       Univerisity of Macau        Univerisity of Macau         Sun Yat-Sen University

                                Publicity Chairs

















                                       Prof. Yuan WU              Prof. Dingqi YANG
                                       Univerisity of Macau        Univerisity of Macau

                                Local Arrangement Chairs

















                                     Prof. Qingqing WU            Prof. Xiaowei WU
                                       Univerisity of Macau        Univerisity of Macau]]></page><page Index="65"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="66"><![CDATA[]]></page></pages></Search>